[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f4", "question": "What chess piece has a horse's head?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96f2d23c87fd04dd15e40", "question": "What year did the Times Square Ball Drop first take place?", "answer": "1907, welcoming 1908", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21e", "question": "What city was Indira Gandhi killed in?", "answer": "New Delhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a6", "question": "What plant does the Boll Weevil destroy?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77025eec85e375820b2f6", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most populous island?", "answer": "Java, Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0de0dfcbed638185eaa11", "question": "What was the most-visited attraction in the UK in 2017?", "answer": "British Museum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cd", "question": "Who played Sofia in the movie \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5d605dad637d903c8823", "question": "What is the largest city in South America?", "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b301", "question": "In what city is the Schloss Cecilienhof, site of a historic 1945 conference?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96a1823c87fd04dd15e0f", "question": "Who was the youngest declared monarch in history?", "answer": "Mary, Queen Scots", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358c035db0d66a186cb55a", "question": "The \"Arenga Micrantha\" species of flowering plants is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "The Tibetan sugar palm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5bd", "question": "How many canine teeth are there in a normal set of human teeth?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5af", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfdfeacb668d7dfe168b5b0", "question": "The term \"lupine\" refers to which animal?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339946", "question": "What are the names of Brian Wilson\u2019s two brothers in the original lineup of the Beach Boys.", "answer": "Carl and Dennis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f01", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46e", "question": "How many hairs does the average human lose each day?", "answer": "Between 40 and 100", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a7226c0f9723ab15cb5b", "question": "How many zeros are in a quadrillion?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eea", "question": "Mr. Deeds hails from what fictional town?", "answer": "Mandrake Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde4", "question": "Where is the Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Springfield, Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e7", "question": "What year did writer Arthur C. Clarke die?", "answer": "2008", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c6e9877e98cb977789c4", "question": "Where can you find the Dragon Blood Tree", "answer": "Yemen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a913", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7ec7cb24f84e0b9f9ffe7", "question": "Who made the song \"Bad Case of Loving You\" popular?", "answer": "Robert Palmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e2", "question": "Who is the director of the movie \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f4", "question": "What do you have if you are suffering from circadian dysrhythmia?", "answer": "Jet lag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6652d52a821ff76ae8af3", "question": "Which Greek god inspired the Baby New Year?", "answer": "Dionysus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6a", "question": "Who replaces Professor Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c87b877e98cb977789e6", "question": "In which country can you find Piedra del Pe\u00f1ol (also called El Pe\u00f1on de Guatape)?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f95aea455722f97b22684d5", "question": "Which Star Wars character is the first to be partially named after director George Lucas\u2019 son?", "answer": "Dexter Jettster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de2306d333868d34d70f", "question": "How was the German battleship Bismarck disabled during World War II?", "answer": "By attacks of Swordfish aircraft from the British aircraft carrier Oak Royal.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69b3920565ad31a57c75d", "question": "What was the largest battleship in World War II?", "answer": "Yamato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be18", "question": "Which modern instrument was called the sackbut until the nineteenth century?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e5", "question": "In \"Rocky 3\" what does Apollo Creed give as a gift before he fights \"Clubber\" Lang?", "answer": "Boxing trunks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f9df01dd7bf43be5e84f", "question": "As of 2020, what is the name of the largest submarine in the world?", "answer": "Dmitriy Donskoy, TK-208", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae38", "question": "What first lady was nicknamed the \"Steel Magnolia\"?", "answer": "Rosalynn Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa43", "question": "What geographic term describes a hill with sharply sloping sides and a flat top?", "answer": "Butte", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad7", "question": "What \"Saturday Night Live\" castmember played Sean Connery in their Celebrity Jeopardy skits?", "answer": "Darrell Hammond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdaffe65ff7d326b622a5e", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a8", "question": "In what US state is Dulles International Airport located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99cbd21a8909e5c332d39", "question": "Corsica is part of which country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a00d6c0f9723ab15cb32", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fcc1b64c97eb73f6a51a271", "question": "Who said, \"Love the life you live. Live the life you love\"?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baae", "question": "What company helped the US Army Corps of Engineers develop the \"walkie-talkie\" in the early 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Motorola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fd", "question": "What legendary rock band had a drummer nicknamed \"Bonzo\"?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d1195b4fea7fe947a2228e", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d2", "question": "\"The Running of the Bulls\" event is held in what Spanish city?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea1", "question": "Which was the oldest Marx brother?", "answer": "Chico", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb09", "question": "What do pumpkins grow on?", "answer": "Vines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd6c97e83c707845b216e", "question": "When was the first Masters Tournament played?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdb", "question": "What is Canberra's Telstra Tower also known as?", "answer": "Black Mountain Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d06cda870e6f05ba600855", "question": "What is the capital of The Gambia?", "answer": "Banjul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3f", "question": "What TV show's eateries include The Brick tavern and Roslyn's Cafe?", "answer": "Northern Exposure", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c27", "question": "What is the oldest symphony orchestra in the US?", "answer": "New York Philharmonic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd69f806c0f9723ab15cb2b", "question": "Who was the final Emperor of India?", "answer": "George VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27f", "question": "What is the oldest and most numerous class of animals?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943f", "question": "What song do the soldiers sing walking through the rubble of Hue in the movie Full Metal Jacket?", "answer": "The Mickey Mouse Club theme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f6facee580c7f8fd1e5d", "question": "What does \"M&Ms\" stand for in the candy with the same name?", "answer": "Mars & Murrie's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab8", "question": "When was SIlent Night written?", "answer": "Christmas Eve, 1818", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2b", "question": "What is sometimes known as Goober Grease?", "answer": "Peanut Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38d", "question": "What is gymnophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Nudity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a162ac7f01ec323f8491725", "question": "In 1967 what new safety measure and device were introduced to the UK?", "answer": "Blood alcohol level and the breathalyzer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173fcf44491cbd7c5a17b6", "question": "What is the name of the pagan festival that used to be held during the same period as Valentine's Day?", "answer": "Lupercalia was a festival dedicated to Faunus, the Roman god of agriculture. It was held the middle of February.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339117", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "1896", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339499", "question": "In what city did Ann Romano raise her two daughters on the show \"One Day at a Time\"?", "answer": "Indianapolis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe771d1eec85e375820b300", "question": "Which country hosts the world's highest marathon?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffb", "question": "Who was the son of Saturn and Ops, and the husband of Juno?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f72e9a9e54d890926f6ee", "question": "What is the only country that displays the Bible on its national flag?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98f", "question": "What is the study of moths and butterflies called?", "answer": "Lepidopterology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66f", "question": "Washington D.C. is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d7", "question": "What were the New England Patriots named prior to the 1971 season?", "answer": "Boston Patriots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabf", "question": "Which Canadian island is named after the father of Queen Victoria?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95be7ccba3ffe45786e3", "question": "What do you add to Advocaat to make a Snowball\u00a0cocktail?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21a", "question": "What Labrador retriever supplanted Socks the cat as the Clintons' favorite pet in 1997?", "answer": "Buddy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bd", "question": "What US territory\u2019s official motto is \"Where America\u2019s Day Begins\"?", "answer": "Guam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9b27ebfabb9c85d8a982", "question": "Which Hollywood celebrity was born Dino Crocetti in 1917?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56a", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for the state of Virginia?", "answer": "VA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a2", "question": "Which player won her last tennis Grand Slam Tournament in Paris in 1999?", "answer": "Steffi Graf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1c", "question": "What German composer wrote \"Ode to Joy\"?", "answer": "Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c138", "question": "What is a \"kiwano\" a type of?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e93a594d6f11f394a3b2d53", "question": "What sport was Arthur Ashe associated with?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f44", "question": "\"Pee-Wee's Big Adventure\" is to recover what beloved stolen item?", "answer": "His bike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adba", "question": "What was the first US city to have a subway system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c0", "question": "What \"island\", the southern-most tip of Brooklyn, has three miles of famous boardwalk?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c315", "question": "What is the number 3.14 known as?", "answer": "Pi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2e", "question": "What popular cocktail does James Bond likes \"shaken, not stirred\"?", "answer": "The Martini", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81e", "question": "In what state was the transcontinental railroad completed in 1869, with the hammering of the Golden Spike?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010ca2e0775fa611bce67f4", "question": "Which famed beauty company was named in part for its founder's sister?", "answer": "Maybelline -- Thomas Lyle Williams developed a product for darkening eyebrows and eyelashes and named it after his sister Mabel.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6e", "question": "At what movie's climax does Mookie throw a garbage can through the front window of Sal's Pizzeria?", "answer": "Do the Right Thing's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597de06177980686f722d189", "question": "The modern day sandwich was created during which century?", "answer": "18th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06a", "question": "Which Major League pitcher accumulated the most victories from 2000-09?", "answer": "Andy Pettitte", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d13", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Adventure Home\"?", "answer": "Free Willy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc60eec223966ae8f8886", "question": "What is the first name of Tyler Durden's girlfriend in the film \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Maria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac9", "question": "What chemical element is symbolized with Sn?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35d", "question": "Who was the first American scientist to win a Nobel prize?", "answer": "Albert Michelson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff1420ab0ee8c595b6d39aa", "question": "Who designed the logo for Old Dutch Cleanser?", "answer": "Georgia O'Keefe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2da", "question": "What is the monarch butterfly sometimes called?", "answer": "Milkweed butterfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c058", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Japan?", "answer": "Green pheasant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b358c2c5db0d66a186cb55b", "question": "Popular in the Balkans, what type of beverage is the \"Rakia\"?", "answer": "Fruit brandy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47423f8e329de4f877899", "question": "How many litres does a Nebuchadnezzar contain?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea8", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"On Golden Pond\"?", "answer": "Henry Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601219dd63c99d48cd169afc", "question": "What is a haboob?", "answer": "A type of sand storm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecd", "question": "Who fights crime alongside a German shepherd named Ace?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac22", "question": "Which ocean does Suriname have direct water access to?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b050", "question": "Whose assassination brought Hosni Mubarak to power in Egypt?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94b", "question": "What type of food is Taramasalata?", "answer": "Cured cod roe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b00", "question": "Which character killed Fyodor Karamazov?", "answer": "Smerdyakov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be9", "question": "Which instrument does the Leader of an orchestra play?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfff3a1cf6db9ac4808d0c", "question": "What is the largest city in the contiguous United States in terms of area?", "answer": "Jacksonville, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc2e", "question": "What year did Barbie doll first appear on the market?", "answer": "1959", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef96c96ce05a3942286ea1", "question": "Which martial art does Miss Piggy practice?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c57c877e98cb977789b0", "question": "Where is Eternal Flame Falls?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339468", "question": "What Tom Cruise movie takes place in the year 2054?", "answer": "Minority Report", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b69", "question": "What was the first sports-themed movie to win the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Rocky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339277", "question": "In the Harry Potter series, who sings \"I killed Sirius Black\" to infuriate Harry?", "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d31", "question": "What was the original title of the novel \"Pride & Prejudice\"?", "answer": "First Impressions", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55c", "question": "In what direction do most cyclones whirl in the Southern Hemisphere?", "answer": "Clockwise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339062", "question": "Pan is the Greek god of what?", "answer": "Wild, shepherds and flocks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7c", "question": "Freetown is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Sierra Leone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4b", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Lock, Stock, and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "Vinnie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7475a9e54d890926f6f7", "question": "Buchaechum is a traditional Korean what?", "answer": "Fan dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb3", "question": "Robert Plant was the lead singer for what rock band from 1968 to 1980?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3613815febcc896f9263", "question": "Terence Nelhams-Wright became better knows as who?", "answer": "Adam Faith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5526ce05a3942286ebd", "question": "Which meal made the flight crew and some of the passengers ill in the comedy \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911f", "question": "What novel about social conventions did E. M. Forster publish in 1910?", "answer": "Howards End", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136fc1138175489539637b", "question": "What item gives the Green Lantern his power?", "answer": "Ring -- Turns out the key to being one of the most powerful superheroes in the DC universe is the ability to accessorize.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4b58b8198b9a2b077962", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which global conflict?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22e", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max 2\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76c7beec85e375820b2d2", "question": "In what museum will you find Vincent Van Gogh's painting \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Museum of Modern Art, NYC", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25984b63e5727cf5a484f", "question": "What year did Toni Braxton release the hit song \"Un-Break My Heart\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7be", "question": "What is measured in Becquerels?", "answer": "Radioactivity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25790b63e5727cf5a4843", "question": "What year did Funko introduce \"Pop! Vinyl\" line of figurines?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636f3c967692ea851899b5", "question": "The average American will eat 35,000 what in a lifetime?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ad56cb8751d53e7d7610", "question": "What name is shared by an 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab58", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic has Tashkent as its capital?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7c0962b316f4693fb6797", "question": "What app, a monster hit in 2016, has been credited with teaching Americans the metric system?", "answer": "Pok\u00e9mon GO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9dda8e748bb36357acde2", "question": "What subatomic particle determines isotope?", "answer": "Neutron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff6", "question": "What happened to the Liberty Bell in 1835?", "answer": "It cracked", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e3", "question": "What bluegrass/folk/country singer is often backed by a band called Union Station?", "answer": "Alison Krauss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3e97c73aa70ea0b70af8", "question": "What was the first European name for Hawaii?", "answer": "Captain James Cook, the first European to visit the islands, named them \"the Sandwich islands\" to honor the Earl of Sandwich.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b8", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Who Made Who\"?", "answer": "AC/DC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c780", "question": "Part of Dr. Eugene Shoemaker's ashes are buried at what unique place?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b371201c3f17ccc40c8e1d", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc68", "question": "What college did Brett Favre attend and play football for?", "answer": "Southern Mississippi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf0", "question": "What popular actor won Western Australia's junior chess championship at age 10?", "answer": "Heath Ledger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a622a2ebb971c1417fb8c", "question": "Which French district does Claret come from?", "answer": "Bordeaux", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"honcho\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ef6406d333868d34d778", "question": "What kind of grass has been used at Wimbledon since 2002?", "answer": "Ryegrass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75d", "question": "In the eye, what is the more common name for the condition also known as \"lens opacity\"?", "answer": "Cataract", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f166daf7c52aae91cc07b3", "question": "Which drug, later found to have devastating side effects, was launched in 1957 to help pregnant women overcome morning sickness?", "answer": "Thalidomide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7a", "question": "What word describes a cut of steak containing both the T-\u00adbone and the tenderloin?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8d", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Goodbye, Mr. Chips\"?", "answer": "Greer Garson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81e", "question": "What song contains the line \"I feel stupid and contagious\"?", "answer": "Smells Like Teen Spirit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ea", "question": "What US state has been led by Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba42", "question": "What is the eagle in the Great Seal of the United States holding in its right talon?", "answer": "Olive branch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd73ae347d002c297e4c0", "question": "Which is the rainiest US state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98e", "question": "What is Lepidopterology the study of?", "answer": "Moths and butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb34", "question": "In the late 1990\u2019s, what candy bar used the ad slogan \"Two for me, none for you\"?", "answer": "Twix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067e3dff9c0647b50a8078", "question": "What were the names of the official mascots of the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Vinicius and Tom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e4b4fe83fe1f2a824bb6", "question": "At what conference did the Allies set the terms for the Japanese surrender?", "answer": "The Potsdam Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feb33a97e83c707845b20c4", "question": "Guy Bailey, Roy Hackett and Paul Stephenson made history in 1963, as part of a protest against a bus company that refused to employ black and Asian drivers in which UK city?", "answer": "Bristol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aca001dd7bf43be5e76f", "question": "The pavlova dessert is named after a professional in what artistic field?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd4c9ec223966ae8f88cd", "question": "What was the first Disney animated film based on the life of a real person?", "answer": "\"Pocahontas\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b68e01dd7bf43be5e7de", "question": "What was the first Hot Wheels car?", "answer": "Camaro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c35e89a6b7193fa56721f83", "question": "How many strings are on a baritone ukulele?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8de", "question": "What animals teeth were used as knife blades by Natives?", "answer": "Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73433eec85e375820b230", "question": "Who was the overall commander of the Pacific Fleet during World War II?", "answer": "Admiral Chester Nimitz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad4", "question": "What creatures does an ichthyologist study?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd7ecec223966ae8f88d9", "question": "Simone Biles was the first woman to do what in official competition?", "answer": "Land a triple-double", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0b", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by BuzzBee?", "answer": "Honey Nut Cheerios", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4c", "question": "Krist Novoselic is best known as being the bass player for what former band?", "answer": "Nirvana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdff5ae1cf6db9ac4808cec", "question": "Which city served as the capital of West Germany?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339928", "question": "What was the name of Phoebe\u2019s twin sister on \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Ursula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7f", "question": "What nickname was given to President Andrew Jackson?", "answer": "Old Hickory", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d4d62596a59cbdfbd3a8", "question": "What is another word for \u201cadditive manufacturing\u201d?", "answer": "3D printing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c390", "question": "What treat takes its name from a drink the Aztecs called Xocoatl?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bd", "question": "What is the longest word that can be spelled using only the letters in the top row of a QWERTY keyboard?", "answer": "Typewriter, peppertree, perpetuity, prerequire, proprietor, repertoire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b411", "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?", "answer": "1968", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339615", "question": "Rogers is the last name of which Scooby-Doo character?", "answer": "Shaggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd19", "question": "What vegetable is found in dishes served \"Florentine\" style?", "answer": "Spinach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc0", "question": "In Greek Mythology, what hung from an oak tree in the grove of Ares in Colchis, guarded by a dragon?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c42", "question": "Mort Goldman is the father of which supporting character in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Neil Goldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c510", "question": "In what century did the Dodo bird become extinct?", "answer": "17th", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b415", "question": "How did UN Secretary General Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld die in September, 1961?", "answer": "In a plane crash", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d36", "question": "Anne Hathaway was married to what famous English poet?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339125", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049aaecf93664eb1048699", "question": "Who was Joe\u2019s co-creator for the character of Superman?", "answer": "Jerry Siegel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b8", "question": "What is Dr. Zhivago's first name?", "answer": "Yuri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7e957b24f84e0b9f9ffcc", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b530", "question": "What color is bianco wine?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35e", "question": "What is the dog breed \"Borzoi\" sometimes called?", "answer": "Russian wolfhound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eba", "question": "What happens to Neo twice in a row that clues Trinity in to a glitch in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "A black cat passes him", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b5", "question": "Who did Ed Wood meet in the movie by the same name?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85e", "question": "Which European country is often referred to as the \"Battlefield of Europe\"?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae2", "question": "A \"Tiercel\" is the traditional term for a male what?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173d2b44491cbd7c5a17aa", "question": "What is the oldest active international airline?", "answer": "KLM Royal Dutch Airlines -- Founded in 1919, KLM is also the\u00a0oldest airline in the world\u00a0still operating under its original name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad39", "question": "What farm animal did George Washington introduce to the US?", "answer": "The mule", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c758", "question": "What vitamin, found in carrots, helps maintain the acuity of your vision?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ec", "question": "The Kung San people live in what area of Africa?", "answer": "Kalahari Desert in Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d98df08b8581f80b092b1", "question": "What day did Donald Trump assume office as the 45th President of the United States?", "answer": "January 20, 2017", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfba", "question": "What is a Ramekin?", "answer": "A small casserole dish\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5941281cbab1e6f9796f1b5a", "question": "In what sport with animals do you find \"coursing\"?", "answer": "Greyhound racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea2", "question": "What magazine ran the famous cover of a very pregnant Demi Moore in the buff?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008851cf842fa4c4ba9688", "question": "In which country is the Commandaria wine region?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d93", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Dennis Coles?", "answer": "Ghostface Killah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b371951c3f17ccc40c8e1f", "question": "Which Irish poet said \"There are no strangers here; Only friends you have not yet met.\"?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "art"}, {"id": "60160011fe83fe1f2a824c52", "question": "Who is officially the patron saint of May Day?", "answer": "Saint Joseph, the husband of the Virgin Mary, was made the patron saint of May Day in 1955 due to his perceived work ethic.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea31c0ff048f679a45aae4", "question": "What is the most common form of stalactites?", "answer": "Speleothems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb0", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bloody Mary?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eff", "question": "What artist painted himself sketching on the far right edge of his painting \"The Gross Clinic\"?", "answer": "Thomas Eakins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec7908d98002fdd633bc", "question": "Who played the character of Rose in the 1953 film \"Niagara\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bf", "question": "How old was Marilyn Monroe when she died?", "answer": "36", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955d", "question": "What is the sport in the movie \"Field of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ba", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the west?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a3", "question": "The annual Miss America Pageant is held in what city?", "answer": "Atlantic City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c3", "question": "Kelsey Grammar sings and plays the theme song for which TV show?", "answer": "Frasier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a124", "question": "What do the prisoners call the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd4", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"P\"?", "answer": "Papa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba61f874c93a3298b2156", "question": "What defined as \"the ratio between a circle's circumference and its diameter\"?", "answer": "Pi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb61365dad637d903c882e", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339152", "question": "What year did Stephen King publish the horror novel \"Pet Sematary\"?", "answer": "1983", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23a", "question": "What Australian rock band release the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f122ff048f679a45aaae", "question": "Zoophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c354", "question": "The tranquilizer diazepam is better known by what trademarked name?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b36d01dd7bf43be5e7af", "question": "A clowder is a name given to a group of what?", "answer": "Domestic cats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a150cf93664eb10486be", "question": "The \"Port Malabar Invitational\" golf tournament was last played in what year?", "answer": "1969", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067987ff9c0647b50a804f", "question": "In March, 2016, former politician Radovan Karadzic was sentenced to 40 years in prison for genocide and crimes against humanity committed during what war?", "answer": "Bosnian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eed", "question": "What two late-1950s Broadway musicals featured songs titled \"Maria\"?", "answer": "West Side Story and The Sound of Music", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a7", "question": "How many singers are in a sextet?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60077f9fbd51d85e222ab63e", "question": "What late 19th-century French painter was known for his pictures of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas is acknowledged as the master of drawing human figures in motion. The female ballet dancer became his favorite theme.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45b", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?", "answer": "Au", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d470c8f8e329de4f877895", "question": "What war lasted from June 5 to June 10, 1967?", "answer": "Six-Day War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93f", "question": "How many laps must a driver survive to win the Indianapolis 500?", "answer": "200", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef922d6ce05a3942286e81", "question": "Who did ESPN name the greatest athlete of the 20th century?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8d", "question": "What did Benjamin Franklin do on April 17, 1790?", "answer": "He died", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b274", "question": "What army occupied Addis Ababa in May 1936?", "answer": "Italy's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c800", "question": "By what common name is sodium bicarbonate otherwise known?", "answer": "Baking Soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3e", "question": "What does pink kryptonite do to Superman?", "answer": "It turns him temporarily gay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab0", "question": "Limnology is the study of what?", "answer": "Inland waters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf506ce05a3942286efe", "question": "Who played the female lead in the film \"Man on Fire\"?", "answer": "Dakota Fanning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30f", "question": "Who sang the 1979 song \"Family Tradition\"?", "answer": "Hank Williams Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc2", "question": "Who is the Greek god of love?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f7", "question": "Whose treasure is said to be the subject of the \"Treasure Island\" map?", "answer": "Captain Flint's", "category": "arts"}]